Christmas is celebrated in many cultures
around the world in many different ways.
But there is one tradition common
to all of them, giving gifts.
Why is that?
What's the connection
between gifts and Christmas.
It started with the gifts God gave to all
of us, the universe, galaxies, stars,
animals, the Earth we live on,
the very gift of life.
These are all gifts
given by a God who loves us,
knows us, and wants us to know him.
But something has gone wrong.
We have turned away from the one
who gave us these gifts.
We have treated them
with carelessness and neglect.
We've even convinced ourselves they
weren't gifts at all, that they
just happened and they mean nothing.
Thus, we have become alienated
from our maker and from one another.
So what does all this
have to do with Christmas?
2000 years ago,
a baby was born in an insignificant
town ruled by a powerful empire.
Christmas is the celebration of his birth.
Why was he so special that we
now celebrate his birth today?
We celebrate because even though we have
turned our back on him,
God decided to give us the best
gift of all, the gift of himself.
He came down to Earth as a human being
to live and die and rise again,
all to show us that he knows us and loves
us and gives each one of us
the opportunity to know him.
His name is Jesus.
And today, Jesus wants to give each one
of us a new gift,
the gift of life and a fresh start,
the gift of forgiveness and a personal
relationship with our maker,
and the promise of eternal life.
Jesus is the gift we
celebrate at Christmas.